Guide to the Carol Georgette Lake Bradley memoirs, 1922-1974, 2010-2021 RL.00140
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Carol Georgette Lake Bradley memoirs
1922-1974, 2010-2021
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bradley, Carol Georgette Lake
RL.00140
9.75 Linear Feet 9 boxes
19.75 Gigabytes 11 optical disks (DVD) 2,683 electronic files (.jpeg, .tif, .pdf, .exif, .doc)
Carol Georgette Lake Bradley (1922-2006) was a distinguished graduate of Duke University, class of 1943. Collection consists of ten handwritten spiral-bound volumes containing her memoirs, in which she describes in detail her childhood, school years, World War II, experiences at Duke University, marriage, motherhood, and teaching career. Includes a narrative on the death of one of her children from polycystic kidney disease. Filed inside the volumes are letters, photographs, clippings, programs, and other memorabilia. Related materials, created by Bradley's family, comprise transcriptions, printed digital scans of the pages, and over 2500 electronic files, chiefly photographic images and texts such as transcriptions and indexes. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture at Duke University.
Biographical Note
Carol Georgette Lake Bradley (1922-2006) was raised in New Jersey and was a distinguished graduate of Duke University (class of 1943).
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact a reference archivist before coming to use these records.
Provenance
The Carol Georgette Lake Bradley memoirs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from 2010-2022.
Collection Overview
Collection consists of ten handwritten spiral-bound volumes containing the memoirs of Duke alumna Carol Georgette Lake Bradley (1922-2006), in which she describes in detail her childhood, school years, World War II, experiences at Duke University, marriage, motherhood, and teaching career. Includes a narrative on the death of one of her children from polycystic kidney disease. Filed inside the volumes are letters, photographs, clippings, programs, and other memorabilia.The volumes include photographs, letters, programs, clippings, and other memorabilia that have been tipped in or loosely inserted between the pages.
From about 2010 to 2017, Bradley's family transcribed, scanned, and indexed all of the memoirs; these additional resources are also part of the collection. Electronic files originally on 11 DVDs have been migrated to a library server; file contents are open to research and include scans of photographs, text, and memorabilia.
Families -- United States -- 20th century; High school students -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Women -- Personal narratives; Women -- United States -- Personal narratives; Women -- United States -- Social conditions -- 20th century; World War, 1939-1945; New Jersey -- Social life and customs; United States -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Autobiographies; Digital images; DVDs; Electronic records; Memoirs; Duke University -- Students -- Social life and customs; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Bradley, Carol Georgette Lake; Duke University. Library -- History; Barringer High School (Newark, N.J.) -- History; Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae
- Book 1, 1922-1935, 1 box
  Scope and Contents
  Volume 1 of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoirs contains narrative and photographs relating to her childhood in New Jersey, including family life; her grandmother; dancing school; her childhood homes on Washington Ave., Woodside Ave., and Ridge Street, in Newark; and her time at Barringer High School, also in Newark. Includes inserted photographs and other memorabilia. Bradley frequently recorded song lyrics, movies she attended, and favorite outings in Newark.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Electronic files can only be accessed in the Rubenstein reading room. To request access, please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use these materials.
  - Spiral notebook, 1922-1935 (Box 2)
  - Transcription, digital images, index, 2010-2012; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Book 1: 1922-1935 (electronic records), 2010-2012; .759 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 178 files (137 jpeg; 35 tif; 6 pdf)
    - CLB Book 01 - Notebook Transcription and Index (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL00140-OP-0001)
    - CLB Book 01 - Page Scans JPEG (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL00140-OP-0001)
    - CLB Book 01 - Photo Scans TIFF (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL00140-OP-0001)
    - CLB Book 01 - Photo Scans TIFF Thumbnail Images (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL00140-OP-0001)
- Book 2, 1935-1942, 1 box
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes narrative notebooks and materials from Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's years in high school at Barringer High School in New Jersey, as well as her first through third years as a college student at Duke University. Materials found interfiled in the notebooks include photographs, letters, newspaper clippings, postcards, brochures, programs, and other ephemera. Bradley discusses her family, social life and schoolwork, and other extracurricular activities such as her dancing, travels, friends, and dates.
  Bradley's memoirs about Duke University from 1939-1942 include her impressions of the campus, including the East and West Campuses, the women's dormitories Aycock and Bassett, and the rules and regulations of the Women's College; her classes and her professors; Duke's fraternities and sororities; her dating and social life, including her attendance at dances, church, and football games; the bombing of Pearl Harbor in 1941; food rationing, air raid drills, and train travel during World War II; and other stories about her time at Duke. Notable descriptions include details about her work at the Women's College Library (now Lilly Library); her course schedules and homework assignments; her membership in the Modern Dance Group, the Varsity Club, and Hoof 'n' Horn; and the Cotton Pickers Ball fire of 1941.
  - Spiral notebook, 1935-1942 (Box 1)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, and index, 2010-2012; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Book 2: 1935-1939-1945, Barringer High School and Duke (electronic records), 2010; 1 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 286 files (128 exif; 86 jpeg; 67 tif; 5 pdf)
    - CLB-02-000 Index-Ephemera and Photographs.pdf (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0010)
    - CLB-02-000 Index-JPG List.pdf (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0010)
    - CLB-02-000 Index-TIF Thumbnails.pdf (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0010)
    - CLB-02-000 Notebook-Transcription.pdf (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0010)
    - JPEGs and Tiff Files (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0010)
  - Book 2 - revised: 1935-1939-1945, Barringer High School and Duke (electronic records), 2010-2012; 1 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 285 files (128 exif; 86 jpeg; 67 tif; 4 pdf)
    - CLB Book 2 - Jpeg Page Scans (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0002)
    - CLB Book 2 - Tiff Images (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0002)
    - CLB Book 2 - Transcription (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0002)
- Book 3, 1942-1944, 1 box
  This volume includes narrative and photographs of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's final years at Duke, particularly her courtship, engagement, and marriage to Floyd H. Bradley Jr., nicknamed "Pete." She writes about dating Pete at Duke, his entering the U.S. Army Air Corps, their long-distance relationship, and their secret elopement in Wyoming in 1944. The memoir includes inserted correspondence, photographs, and clippings. Among the topics discussed are her election to the Kappa Delta Pi honor society, her classes and teaching exercises, popular songs and movies from the period, dances she attended, and other social activities she participated in while enrolled at Duke. Also included are photographs and descriptions of her friends, Pete, and her graduation from Duke in May 1943.
  The volume also includes details on Bradley's search for a teaching position following graduation, her visits with Pete and his family while he was in training, and her work as a teacher in Wharton and Bernardsville, New Jersey. Unbound materials consist largely of letters and clippings.
  - Spiral notebook, 1942-1944 (Box 3)
  - Unbound materials, transcriptions, digital images, index, 2010-2012; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Book 3: 1941-1944, Pete--B'ville (electronic records), 2010-2012; 1 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 183 files (126 jpeg; 51 tif; 1 exif; 4 pdf)
    - CLB Book 3 - Jpeg Images (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0003)
    - CLB Book 3 - Tiff Images (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0003)
    - CLB Book 3 - Transcription (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0003)
- Book 4, 1944-1948, 1 box
  This volume includes Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoir and narrative for the years 1944-1948, focusing on her teaching and work experiences; her formal wedding to Pete Bradley; being stationed in Texas; the birth of their first child, Steven Harold; and the conclusion of World War II and the couple's return to New Jersey. She writes about finding housing in the post-war period, Steven's health problems, Pete's finishing his B.A. at Rutgers, and his work at Prudential Insurance Company. The volume concludes with anecdotes about their life in Ocean Grove, including Steven's favorite songs, games, and activities.
  - Spiral notebook, 1944-1948 (Box 3)
  - Unbound materials, transcriptions, digital images, index, 2010-2012; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Book 4: 1944-1948 (electronic records), 2010-2013; 2 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 251 files (151 jpeg; 96 tif; 4 pdf)
    - CLB Book 4 - Notebook Transcription and Index (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0004)
    - CLB Book 4 - Page Scans Jpeg (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0004)
    - CLB Book 4 - Photo Scans Tiff (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0004)
- Book 5, 1945-1951
  Volume 5 of the memoirs of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley continues her account of the early years of the Bradley family. She describes buying their first house in the suburb of Livingston, NJ and details the process of decorating and furnishing it. Bradley writes about settling into the new community. This volume also describes the birth of Floyd Bradley III, though it does not detail much about his early life. Most of the volume is dedicated to anecdotes about the last few years of Steven's life, the details of his death at age seven, and his funeral. Bradley writes extensively about the open casket ceremony hosted in her home and the cherry tree memorial that friends and family planted in Steve's honor. Many of the notebook's later pages are made up of correspondence and newpaper clippings about the funeral and the memorial.
  - Spiral notebook, 1945-1951 (Box 4)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, index, 2010-2012 (Box 4)
  - Book 5: 1945-1953 (electronic records), 2011-2013; 2 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 239 files (118 jpeg; 116 tif; 5 pdf)
    - CLB Book 5 - Notebook Transcription and Index (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0005)
    - CLB Book 5 - Page Scans Jpeg (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0005)
    - CLB Book 5 - Photo Scans Tiff (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0005)
- Book 6, 1952-1960
  In Volume 6 of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoirs, she recounts the birth of her third child, Lynette, and describes the early childhood of Floyd and Lynette. She writes about her children's love of dancing and Floyd's interest in westerns, playing guitar, and the Boy Scouts. Bradley also describes family vacations in Cape Cod and Miami. She writes about obtaining her master's degree and getting her first post, teaching second grade at the brand new Collins School, where she wrote and directed the first school play (script included). Bradley remembers deciding to move to a bigger house in Short Hills. This volume contains photographs of birthday parties, vacations, and holidays as well as class photos of her children and a few of Floyd's report cards.
  - Spiral notebook, 1953-1960 (Box 4)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, index, 2010-2012 (Box 4)
  - Book 6: 1953-1960 (electronic records), 2011-2013; 4 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 374 files (132 jpeg; 233 tif; 5 pdf; 4 doc)
    - CLB Book 6 - Notebook Transcription and Index (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0006)
    - CLB Book 6 - Page Scans Jpeg (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0006)
    - CLB Book 6 - Photo Scans Tiff (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0006)
- Book 7, 1960-1964
  In Volume 7 of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoirs, she describes the family's new house on Hickory Rd., in Short Hills, N.J., provides information for nearby Sweets Restaurant, notes the transfer of her teaching position to Hartshorn School and the children's school assignments, and reports on Lynette and Floyd's schoolwork and pastimes, including painting, ice skating, dancing, piano lessons, and scouting. She also outlines plans for a trip to Hawaii, and details treatments used following Lynette's diagnosis with epilepsy. There are photographs of the new house and parties held there, and report cards and notes of appreciation are pasted in.
  - Spiral notebook, 1960-1964 (Box 5)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, index, 2010-2012 (Box 5)
  - Book 7: 1960-1964 (electronic records), 2013-2015; 2 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 220 files (108 jpeg; 107 tif; 5 pdf)
    - CLB Book 7 - Page Scans Jpeg (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0007)
    - CLB Book 7 - Photo Scans Tiff (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0007)
    - CLB Book 7 - Notebook Transcription and Index (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0007)
    - CLB Book 7 - Duke Letter.pdf (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0007)
- Book 8, 1964-1965
  Volume 8 of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoirs provides an account of their family vacation to Hawaii, Sequoia National Park, Disneyland, and Las Vegas. In addition, she outlines Lynette's ongoing treatment for epilepsy, continues to follow the school careers and other accomplishments of her children, and describes parties held and attended, as well as the family's purchase of a dog. The volume includes extensive photographs of the family vacation, parties held and attended, and the dog, Sybil. Also pasted in are letters written by Carol and by the children.
  - Spiral notebook, 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, index, 2010-2012 (Box 5)
  - Book 8: 1964-1965 (electronic records), 2013-2015; 2 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 238 files (128 jpeg; 102 tif; 6 pdf; 2 txt)
    - CLB Book 8 - Notebook Transcription and Index (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0008)
    - CLB Book 8 - Page Scans Jpeg (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0008)
    - CLB Book 8 - Photo Scans Tiff (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0008)
    - CLB Book 8 - Transmittal Letter to Laura (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0008)
- Book 9, 1965-1967
  In Volume 9 of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoirs, she outlines the family's continuing attempts to get Lynette's epilepsy under control. She also reports on her teaching, including the producing and writing of school plays (scripts included) as well as her supervising a student teacher. She also describes the family's vacations at Ocean Grove, N.J., their participation in religious activities, and the purchase of a new house. Letters, notes, and clippings are pasted in, along with color photographs, primarily featuring family members.
  - Spiral notebook, 1965-1967 (Box 6)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, index, 2010-2012 (Box 6)
  - Book 9: 1965-1967 (electronic records), 2014-2015; 1 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 165 files (89 jpeg; 70 tif; 6 pdf)
    - CLB Book 9 - Notebook Transcription and Index (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0009)
    - CLB Book 9 - Page Scans Jpeg (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0009)
    - CLB Book 9 - Photo Scans Tiff (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0009)
    - CLB Book 9 - Duke Letter.pdf (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0009)
- Book 10, 1967-1969
  In Volume 10 of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoirs, she recounts a tranquil, happy chapter in her family history. She and her husband are able to buy a new home in Short Hills, NJ, as well as a summer home in Ocean Grove. There are photographs documenting Carol's remodeling and decorating of these new homes, as well as local newspaper clippings highlighting her work on their beach house. Her teenage daughter is healthy and enjoying school. Her son excells academically and is accepted to Yale University, where he matriculates in 1969. Family photographs are tipped in.
  - Spiral notebook, 1967-1969 (Box 7)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, index, 2010-2012 (Box 7)
  - Book 10: 1967-1969 (electronic records), 2016-2017; 3 Gigabytes 1 DVD-RW; 1 optical disk with 264 files (111 jpeg; 146 tif; 7 pdf)
    - CLB Book 10 - Notebook Transcription and Index (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0011)
    - CLB Book 10 - Page Scans Jpeg (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0011)
    - CLB Book 10 - Photo Scans Tiff (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0011)
    - CLB Book 10 - Duke Letter.pdf (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0011)
    - CLB-10-000 Transcription of Notebook - Master Copy.pdf (Digital-materials RL00140-SET-0001, Optical-disc RL.00140-OP-0011)
- Book 11, 1969-1972
  In Volume 11 of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoirs, Carol takes a year off from teaching to help her youngest daughter, Lynette, settle in at Birmingham Southern University. Carol's son, Floyd, is an upperclassman at Yale with interests in economics, business, and law. Carol and her husband Pete are empty-nesters for the first time and go on vacation without their children: a Caribbean cruise.
  - Spiral notebook, 1969-1972 (Box 8)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, index, 2018 (Box 8)
  - Book 11: 1969-1972 (electronic records) (Optical-disc RL00140-OP-0012)
- Book 12, 1972-1974
  In Volume 12 of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoirs, her son Floyd has graduated magna cum laude from Yale and been accepted into the MBA program at Harvard. Her daughter Lynette is enjoying her studies at Birmingham Southern University. Both children are grateful for their parents' financial support of their education. The family vacations in the Caribbean. Carol writes about her educational philosophy and dedication to her second-grade students.
  - Spiral notebook, 1972-1974 (Box 8)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, index, 2020 (Box 8)
  - Book 12: 1972-1974 (electronic records) (Optical-disc RL00140-OP-0013)
- Book 13, 1974-1976
  In Volume 13 of Carol Georgette Lake Bradley's memoirs, the family deals with the loss of loved ones, including Carol's father. Carol's daughter Lynette graduates from Birmingham Southern University, and Floyd has graduated from Harvard Business School. Carol continues her dedication to teaching and contributions to the education profession.
  - Spiral notebook, 1974-1976 (Box 9)
  - Transcriptions, digital images, index, 2021 (Box 9)
  - Book 13: 1974-1976 (electronic records) (Digital-materials RL00140-USB-0001)